我看到你了
I can see you.
出来
Come out.
慢慢地
Slowly.
我看还是免了吧
Yeah, I think I'm gonna pass on that.
《行尸走肉》
(我们在这里拥有很多  人  食物  药品  围墙  一切生存必需品)
卡萝尔
Carol?
你在吗
You here?
楼上
Upstairs.
你好吗
How are you?
见到你真开心
Happy to see you.
发生了什么
What happened?
滑了一跤
Oh, I just slipped.
在建新哨塔的时候
Building a new guard tower.
我去了医务室
I went to the infirmary.
那里现在好安静
It's so quiet over there now.
从灾变一开始我就认识丹妮斯了
I knew Denise since the beginning.
皮特还在的时候  她不太出来
She wasn't around much before Pete, but...
在那之前  她总是待在家里
before that, she just stayed inside.
她总是在读书
She was always-- was always reading something.
她在必要的时候站了出来
And she really stepped up when she had to.
她为我们站了出来
She was there for us.
我不是有意提起这个
I didn't mean to bring it up.
不  只是...
No, it's just--
我一直担心塔拉  担心她得知这事
I just keep thinking about Tara, when she finds out.
一切都会没事的
Hey, everything's gonna be okay.
是啊
Yeah.
真好
This is good.
是啊
Mm, it is.
耶稣证明了自己
Jesus came through.
他们都证明了自己
They all did.
他们会继续证明自己的
And they're all gonna keep coming through.
玛姬让我和格伦
Maggie asked me and Glenn
帮着安置更多的枪桶和哨岗
to help put up more bins and watch points.
别走
S-stick around.
朱迪斯还没醒呢
Judith-- Judith isn't even up yet.
等等  不不不
Wait, no. No, no, no, no.
-是吗  为什么不  -不
- Yeah? Why not? - No.
玛姬给我们排好班了
Maggie has us on a schedule
我可不想惹一个怀孕的女士
and I'm not pissing off a pregnant lady.
是啊
Yeah.
-别惹那个怀孕的女士  -没错
- Not that pregnant lady. - Right.
去吧
Go.
她担心我们遭到袭击
She's worried about an attack.
如果他们来找我们  我们就终结了
When they come for us, we'll end it,
终结这一切
the whole thing.
这次跟以前不一样
This won't be like before.
我们准备妥当
We're putting everything in place
人们现在知道该做什么
and these people know what to do now.
这个世界属于我们
The world's ours,
而且我们知道该如何拿下
and we know how to take it.
我们需要的一切
Everything we need
都在墙内
is right here inside these walls.
我们不会再失去了
We're not losing any of it again.
我不会
I'm not.
不  你不会
No, you're not.
我不会
I'm not.
这些留着  但也应该藏几把
We'll have these, but we should hide a few.
那样的话  我们找得到  外人找不到
That way, we can find them, but strangers can't.
以防有人闯进来
In case anyone gets in.
他们闯不进来的
They won't.
糟了
Oh, no.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
外面
Out.
扯淡  具体去哪
No, shit. You got specifics?
他到底在干什么
What the hell is he doing?
干他不该干的事
Something he shouldn't.
我们得去制止他
We gotta stop him.
给老子也腾个位置
Make room for my freckled ass.
不行
No.
替我站岗  你留下
Cover my watch. You stay.
得有足够人手留在这里
Hey, we should keep numbers here.
我知道达里尔要去哪
I know where Daryl's going.
她什么时候离开的
What time did she leave?
你知道她带了什么吗
Do you know what she took?
她是夜里离开的  我没听见她走
Sometime in the night. I never heard her go,
但她做了一大堆吃的
but she made a bunch of food, you know.
带走了她的背包
She took her pack,
-拿了我一件外套...  -她是步行离开的吗
- one of my coats-- - Did she leave on foot?
我...我不知道
I-- I don't know.
瑞克  我十二点接的班  待到六点
Rick, I took over at 12:00, I was on till 6:00.
我什么也没看见
I never saw anything.
在他们出去之后  前门一直没动静
Front's been quiet since the others left.
什么  谁出去了
What? Who?
达里尔  他出去找昨天那帮救世军寻仇了
Daryl. He went ICBM after the Saviors from yesterday.
格伦  米琼恩  罗西塔
Glenn, Michonne, Rosita,
他们都追出去阻止他了
they all went to shut that shit down.
另一辆车哪去了
Where's the other car?
我们昨天多摆了两辆车
We added two more cars yesterday.
现在有一辆不见了
One of them's missing,
就是摆在那些房子中间的那辆
the one we put right between those houses.
从上面基本看不清那些房子中间的情况
You can barely see between the houses from up top,
特别是在晚上
especially at night.
那张纸条  能给我看看吗
The note, can I see it?
你没看见车头灯车尾灯亮起来吗
You never saw any headlights, taillights?
她很聪明  知道如何掩藏踪迹
She's smart enough to cover her tracks.
她一定是趁着换班的时候溜走的
She must've left during the shift change.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我去找她
I'm gonna go find her.
等等
Wait.
告诉卡尔我马上回来
Tell Carl I'll be back soon.
其他任何人都不准离开
No one else leaves.
全员做好战斗准备
Everyone else stays ready for a fight.
举起手来
Hands up.
求求你们别伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
为何大家总是把情况往最糟的方向想呢
Why does everyone always assume the worst?
你从车里出来如何
How 'bout you come on out?
我只有这辆车
I just have the car.
以及一把对付行尸的小刀  没别的了
And a knife for the dead ones, nothing else.
不  你有情报
Naw, you got information.
比如你是打哪里来的  要到哪里去
Like where you're from, where you're going.
说嘛  这是个孤独的世界
Come on, it's a lonely world.
我们互相认识一下嘛
Let's get to know each other.
我叫希罗
I'm Jiro.
该你了
Your turn.
我谁也不是  真的
I'm nobody, really.
我叫南希  来自蒙特克莱尔
Nancy from Montclair.
但我一直漂泊不定
But I've bounced around a lot since then.
四处奔波
I-- I keep moving.
我没从哪里来  也没打算到哪里去
I'm not really from anywhere. I'm not really going anywhere.
至少我们在一件事上达成了共识
At least we agree on one thing,
蒙特克莱尔来的南希
Nancy from Montclair--
你哪里也去不成
you're not going anywhere.
但你看起来确实像是从某个地方来的
But you do seem like you're from somewhere.
在你离开蒙特克莱尔后  是吧
After Montclair, right?
迈尔斯  那地方叫什么来着
Miles, what's that place called?
那个带栅门的社区
The gated one.
离这12.75公里
12.75 clicks down?
亚历山大
Alexandria.
对  亚历山大
Yeah, Alexandria.
那里的前门外停着一些车  插着木棍
You know, they got some cars out front, spikes through them,
就像你开的这辆一样
just like the one you're driving.
你这样的女人
A woman like you,
手无寸铁  毫无防卫  一无所知
no weapons, no protection, no clue,
真不应该一个人出来
you really shouldn't be out here alone.
我们正要去你们那
You know, we were just on our way to your place.
我们可以送你一程
We can give you a ride back.
也许有你陪着  他们会让我们进去
Maybe they'll let us in if you're with us.
不用这样的
It doesn't have to be this way.
你们可以掉头回家
You could turn back and you could go home.
没人会受伤
Nobody has to get hurt.
看来有人要受伤了
It's looking like someone's gotta get hurt.
求你了
Please.
伙计  不如趁现在抓住她
Man, why don't you just grab her
免得她待会儿晕过去了
before she passes out?
不要  求你们了
Don't, please!
我看到你了
I can see you.
慢慢地出来
Come out slowly.
我看还是免了吧
I think I'm gonna pass on that.
你看起来很疲倦
You look tired.
我们还有很多事要做
We still have a lot to do.
格伦  米琼恩和罗西塔追着达里尔出去了
Glenn, Michonne, and Rosita just took off after Daryl.
我要多轮一班
I'm taking an extra shift.
先来把午餐打包带走
Just packing a lunch before I go back out.
-回见  -你要去哪
- See you later. - Where are you going?
在你休息时帮你轮班
Take your shift while you rest.
伊妮德
Enid...
就几个小时而已
Just for a few hours.
让我帮忙吧
Let me help.
好好休息  吃点泡菜
Put up your feet and eat some pickles.
你用不着跟来的
You didn't have to come.
我们必须试试  就算机会渺茫
We have to try, even if it's a long shot,
就算危机四伏
even if it's dangerous.
轮胎印是向东的
Tire tracks pointed east...
我们去东面
we go east.
你和队伍去的地方  那个救世军的基地
Saviors' compound that you and the group-- that you went to,
那是西面
that was west.
看起来她去了东面
Seems like she went east.
你一点都不了解卡萝尔
You don't even know Carol.
我了解的
Oh, I got to.
了解一点
A little.
你为什么这么做
Why are you doing this?
我所信仰的  未必正确
What I believe-- I'm not right.
不存在所谓的正确
There is no right.
只存在没有拖垮你的错误
There's just the wrong that doesn't pull you down.
它还没有拖垮我
It hasn't pulled me down.
我想它会的
I think it will.
因为我了解你
'Cause I know you.
该死的
God dang--!
天啊
Oh, man.
放弃吧伙计  别挣扎了
Just let it go, man. Just let go.
天啊
God.
在那
There.
我看到了
I see it.
那是她的车
That's her car.
看到她了吗
You see her?
没有
No.
她在哪
Where is she?
救世军之前从山顶寨铁匠那拿过武器
The Saviors were getting weapons from the Hilltop's blacksmith.
这些人是救世军
These men were Saviors.
这里有血
There's blood here.
她可能中枪了
She could've been hit.
我为她感到骄傲
I'm proud of her.
为什么
How's that?
她干掉了四个人
She took four of them down.
那个女人  她非常强大
That woman, she's a force of nature.
她离开是因为她不能再杀人了
She left because she can't anymore.
她信里是这么说的
That's what her letter said.
她能的  因为她必须这样做
She could because she had to.
有些时候你必须这样做
Sometimes you have to.
对面有更多的血
There's more blood opposite these men
一直到田地里
that leads into the field.
可能是卡萝尔留下的踪迹
It's a trail. Could be Carol's.
她可能还活着
She could still be alive.
她不在这
She's not here.
他们的枪很多都不见了
Most of their guns are gone.
-估计她拿走了  -还有这些
- She might've taken them. - Those, too.
也有可能她死在这了
Or she could've died here,
即便她现在不在这
even if she isn't here.
踪迹向这边去了
Trail goes this way.
他们离亚历山大很近
They were close to Alexandria.
他们还有更多人
There's even more of them.
我们没能斩草除根
We didn't end it.
不
No.
你挑起了事端
You started something.
她就死在这里
That's where she died.
好吧  那他肯定是从这里开始的
All right, so he had to start from here.
没错
He did.
德怀特往哪边跑的
Which way did Dwight run?
罗西塔
Rosita?
我们该让他放手去干
We should let him do this.
但他不知道他在干什么
But he doesn't know what he's doing.
我们也不知道
We don't.
或许他这么做  现在是会让你心里好受点
Maybe him trying this makes you feel better about it right now.
或许这会让敌人对我们的了解越来越多
Maybe they keep knowing more about us than we know about them.
或许达里尔会害死自己
Or maybe Daryl's gonna get himself killed.
德怀特往哪边跑的
Which way did Dwight run?
你看清楚点人  混蛋
Watch the hell out, asshole.
我看清楚了  你们不该来的
I did. You shouldn't have come.
你不该离开的
You shouldn't have left.
我之前跟萨沙和亚伯拉罕分开时
When I split off from Sasha and Abraham,
他和那帮女的
he was out there in the woods,
就在那片烧毁的森林里
in that burned-out forest with them girls,
拿枪抵着我头  把我绑起来
put a gun to my head, tied me up.
我当时竟然想去帮他
I even tried to help him.
所以你觉得是你的错吗
So, you think it's your fault?
是啊  我知道就是的
Yeah, I know it is.
我要去做我一开始就该做的事
I'm gonna go do what I should've done before.
怎么  为了她吗
What, for her?
她已经死了
She's gone, man.
你是为了自己才这么做
You're doing this for you.
我不在乎
Man, I don't give a shit.
达里尔
Daryl...
我们得回家  再考虑这些事
we need to get back there and figure this out from home.
我们的家
Our home.
我们需要你  现在家里的人需要我们的保护
We need you, and everyone back there needs us right now.
外面形势不妙
It's-- it's gonna go wrong out here.
我们会报这个仇的  我会的
We'll square it. I will.
我向你保证
I promise you.
回家吧
Just come back.
我做不到
I can't.
-达里尔  -我做不到
- Daryl. - Man, I can't!
我也做不到
I can't either.
问题是  那些人现在可能正往亚历山大去
Thing is, those men could be back in Alexandria right now.
要是他们真去了  就死定了
If they are, they're dead.
但愿不会
I hope not.
我们需要留他们活口
We need them alive.
我们得了解更多情报
We need to find out more.
是啊  没错
Yeah, we do.
我们遇到了彼此
We just got stuck with each other.
算我们走运
We were lucky.
我们一起想办法度难关
We figured it all out together.
我以为我们做到了
I felt like we did.
经历了这么多  真的以为做到了
After everything, we did.
可这个世界与我们想象的不同
The world's not what we thought it was.
山顶寨  救世军  更加复杂
Hilltop, the Saviors, it's bigger.
血迹不多
It's not much.
但如果这是卡萝尔的血
But if it's Carol's,
那她失血有好一会儿了
then she's been bleeding for a while.
你来这儿是因为卡萝尔是你的朋友吗
So, you out here because Carol is your friend?
我来这儿是因为她是我的家人
I'm out here 'cause she's my family.
我在社区找人聊过
I've talked to people back there.
我知道在监狱里发生了什么
I found out about what happened at the prison.
你为什么要驱逐她
How you sent her away.
她杀了你的两个同伴  对吗
She killed two of your people, right?
烧掉了他们的尸体
Burned their bodies.
如果这件事发生在今天
What if that had happened today?
你会杀了她吗
Would you kill her?
如果发生在今天  我会谢谢她
If it happened today, I'd thank her.
或者我会亲自杀了他们
Or I would've killed them myself.
她那样做是对的
She was right to do it.
他们当时病了  散播病毒
They were sick, spreading a disease.
他们撑不下去的
They weren't gonna make it.
是啊  但那时候与现在不同
Yeah, but this was back then.
你也没有杀她
And you didn't kill her.
你把她逐走了  瑞克  然后她回来了
You sent her away, Rick, and she came back.
她回来了  救了你们所有人
And she came back and she saved all y'all.
人是可以回头的  瑞克
People can come back, Rick.
不是她
It's not her.
她才死了不到一天
She couldn't have been dead more than a day.
别紧张  我不会惹什么麻烦
It's okay. I'm not trouble.
我不想惹什么麻烦
I don't want any trouble.
出来  放下你的武器
Come out, drop your weapons.
我做不到
I can't do that.
那些行尸太近了
The wasted are too close.
我只是在找我的马  你看到了吗
I'm just looking for my horse. Have you seen him?
没有
No.
我们在找朋友  你看到她了吗
We're looking for our friend. Have you seen her?
你看到她了吗
Have you seen her?
它们来了
They're coming!
走吧  走吧
Just go! Just go!
站住
Stop!
瑞克
Rick.
我们不知道他是谁
We didn't know who he was.
没错  是山顶寨的武器
Yeah, it's one of the Hilltop's.
就像路上的那根
Like the one on the road.
也许他是救世军的人
Maybe he's one of them.
也许他也在找卡萝尔
Maybe he's looking for Carol, too.
也许那个人只是在找一匹马
Maybe the man is just looking for a horse.
也许他是山顶寨的人  也许他是其他地方的人
Maybe he is from Hilltop. Maybe he's from somewhere else.
我现在不会再冒险了
I don't take chances anymore.
那些人
Those people...
那些狼群
the Wolves...
他们袭击后  我找到了其中一人
after they attacked, I found one of them.
我之前去找你的时候
He had attacked me on the road before,
他在路上袭击过我
when I was trying to find you.
我阻止了他
And I stopped him.
但我放他走了
But I let him live.
袭击过后  他又出现在亚历山大
And then he was there in Alexandria after the attack,
躲在某个褐石屋里  我又阻止了他
hiding in one of the brownstones, so I stopped him again.
我把他击晕了  本来可以杀了他
I knocked him out and I could have killed him.
但所有生命都是宝贵的
But all life is precious.
我把他关在褐石屋的地下室中
Put him in the cell of the brownstone basement.
因为我知道他会改变
'Cause I knew he could change.
我们都会改变
We all can change.
-你在社区里关了一个活的  -是的
- You had one of them alive in the community? - Oh, yeah.
当墙倒下行尸进来时  卡萝尔发现了这事
And when the walls came down and the walkers broke in, Carol found out.
我们打斗了  那个人逃走了
We fought and that man escaped,
而丹妮斯
and Denise...
她来牢房治疗他
she had come to the cell to try and help him
被他抓做人质
and he took her hostage.
然后她和那只狼被行尸包围了
And then she and that Wolf, they got swarmed,
那个人  那个杀人凶手
and that man, that killer,
他救了她的命
he saved her life.
然后丹妮斯才能救了卡尔的命
And then Denise was there to save Carl.
这
It--
这是一场轮回
it's all a circle.
一切都有因果
Everything gets a return.
但事实就是事实
But the fact is the fact.
我确实那样做了
I did what I did.
我留了他一命
I let him live.
你回家吧  瑞克
You go home, Rick.
你开上车  家里需要你
You take the car. You're needed back there.
你不该在外面冒险
You shouldn't be out here taking any more chances.
我不走
I'm not leaving.
-卡萝尔还在外面  -我会找到她
- Carol's still out here. - And I will find her.
总会找到的
Somehow.
你走吧
You go.
你会回来的
You're coming back.
是的
Yeah.
但如果我没回来  别来找我
But if I don't, don't come looking.
拿着
Take it.
-不  我...  -拿着
- No, I-- - Take it.
摩根
Morgan?
那根蛋白棒的确是米琼恩偷的
Michonne did steal that protein bar.
我知道
Oh, I know.
摩根还在外面找
Morgan's still out there looking.
米琼恩回来了吗
Is Michonne here?
她也还在外面
She's still out there, too.
你害怕
You afraid...
回到过去吗
to go back to it?
跟某人太亲近
Let somebody close?
是的  是的
Yeah. Yeah.
我也是
Me, too.
但是现在
But now...
我已经准备好
I think I'm that much more ready
把这世界再捅个窟窿了
to tear the world a brand-new asshole.
快回来了
Any second now.
是啊
Yeah.
快回来了
Any second.
斯科特说你在找我
Scott said you were looking for me?
什么事
What's up?
我需要帮忙
I need some more help.
我喜欢
I like it.
但是为什么
But why?
我必须继续下去
I have to keep going.
我不能让任何东西妨碍我
And I don't want anything getting in my way.
怎么  我剪太短了吗
Man, did I go too short?
我只给我爸爸剪过
I-I only used to cut my dad's.
不  不是因为那个
No, it's not that.
玛姬
Maggie?
Maggie.
玛姬
Maggie!
达里尔
Hi, Daryl.
你死不了
You'll be all right.